Hey everyone, thanks for joining us.
It's Wednesday, August 6th, 2025. You
are watching DProgram with Ted Roll and
John Kuryaku.
>> Welcome back.
>> Full slate here to get into John. Always
a pleasure. Always look forward to this.
>> Oh, Ted, just since we texted each other
this morning, there's been like an
entire show's worth of extra stuff that
has happened over the course of the day.
>> All right, so let's plow into it. Um, in
no particular order really, um, let's
just get into it. I mean, you've, so
Donald Trump is threatening to, uh, take
over to refederalize Washington DC. Um,
you sort of shared a little bit of that
history last time, but maybe you could
do it again. As a New York, I didn't
really know the history. I went back and
read it. Um, but it is fascinating. But
basically um you know Washington DC is
under home rule as it's called. You can
maybe explain what that is. And Trump is
basically really agitated about crime in
the nation's capital
>> for a specific reason.
>> Because of big balls.
>> Yes. Because of big balls. That's right.
>> So Big Balls is the Doge douche who uh
got really famous because of his
nickname. He's been all over social
media and all over uh cable television
uh and comedy shows and stuff. And Big
Balls got carjacked, him and his
girlfriend. And uh he did by 10 youths
uh or so. Uh two are in custody. Um I
mean, all all kidding aside, that's no
fun for anyone.
>> No. And they beat the [__] out of him,
too.
>> And they he and he nobly defended his uh
girlfriend. So,
>> yes,
>> the man has big balls. He's earned his
nickname for real. And uh but Trump with
Trump, it's always personal. If he knows
someone personally involved or he cares
about them, they're a celebrity, then he
then he's pissed off. So
>> take it away, John.
>> So Washington DC license plates say um
taxation without representation because
that's a fact of life here. If you live
in Washington DC, you pay federal income
taxes just like everybody else, but you
don't get a voting member of the House
or two voting members of the US Senate.
So, you're just out of luck. Um, until
1971,
Washington DC was governed by a
congressional committee, the Committee
on District of Columbia Affairs it was
called. And um and then in 1971, the
federal government under that that
paragon of liberalism, Richard Nixon, uh
gave
DC what is called home rule. Home rule
means DC has a mayor who is actually the
the mayor of the city and it has a city
council and it has neighborhood councils
and has all these different bodies that
run the city on a day-to-day basis.
Donald Trump doesn't like that. Donald
Trump wants the Republican House of
Representatives to take over DC again.
And
that idea, which is a terrible idea, got
some energy when Big Balls was
apparently accosted by 10 kids 14, 15,
and 16 years old. There's a picture of
him on Truth Social. They beat the hell
out of him and he's just he has no shirt
on and he's just soaked in blood. It's a
disgusting picture. Um, but there's more
to the story that came out this
afternoon. Somebody leaked to the
Washington Post that in the last couple
of days, Trump held a secret meeting at
the White House to discuss ways to seize
control of the New York mayoral race,
throw Mandani out of the country, and
take over the government of New York.
>> What?
>> Yeah. Now, that's not going to happen.
>> It is patently unconstitutional. It's
the very definition of fascism. It's not
going to happen. But he's trying to
figure out ways to make it happen. It's
far easier to do in Washington DC
because there's a long history of of
federal intervention,
>> right?
>> In fact, even city in the same way that
New York is,
>> it's not. And then even during home rule
when Marian Barry was the mayor, he was
mayor four times. Uh and he was, you
know, snorting crack and cheating on his
wife and drunk at city council meetings.
He would pass out. Um the federal
government didn't do away with home
rule, but it seized budgetary authority.
And so um
and so
for a period of four years, the
government turned budgetary authority
over to a guy who was a CPA. His name
was Anthony um oh shoot, I forget his
name. Anyway, he was just a nerd and he
ran for mayor and won and was an
absolutely fantastic mayor. Anthony
Williams. Anthony Williams. Uh and so DC
got home rule back in its entirety. Now
Trump wants to take it away. This thing
with Manni,
I mean, let's let's call a spade a spade
here. This is only because Mandani is a
Muslim
>> andic socialism.
>> Well, and yeah, and but first of all,
there's no legal basis for deporting
Mandani.
>> He's a US citizen.
>> Yeah. Right. Right.
>> I mean, I guess you can I mean, you can
deport a naturalized citizen. as my mom
if it was a naturalized citizen
constantly reminded me um you know she
was like if if they want they can take
it away that's not true in other
countries like I'm a naturalized French
citizen
>> that's right
>> uh but they you know I can run for
president of France there's no secondass
citizenship there
>> the way we have you know
>> um so yeah so I mean
>> what does this mean I mean what does it
say about the mental state and the
political ideology of the president
entertain such a thought. I mean, you
know, one of the commenters said, uh,
the riots would be insane, and that is
for sure. I don't think we I don't I
think you'd have to go back to the, uh,
draft riots of the Civil War. I mean,
the city would burn. I mean, it's like I
mean, Montani is I mean, people like me
would join the riots. I mean, it's like
Mandani is really popular. Yeah.
>> It's the will of the people. He's going
to be the mayor.
>> Um, And you know, trying to in to keep
Mayor Adams in is already a shocking
move by the establishment because he's
so unpopular. If they backed Cuomo, that
would be a little bit more
understandable. Um, you know, he's
>> and I think it's Ted, you you have much
more experience with this than I do, but
it seems increasingly clear to me day
after day after day that Mandani is
going to be the next mayor of New York.
>> There's no question. Just today, John
Katy Matidis, the the second richest man
in New York. Um, he owns Gristitis and
Red Apple and Wawa and yeah, supermarket
chains. He's a he's the biggest
developer in Brooklyn where Trump is the
biggest developer in uh in Manhattan.
>> He endorsed Well, not really.
>> All that wealth, but it can't buy him
good looks.
>> No, it can't. No. Poor guy. He's the
ugliest man you've ever seen in your
life.
>> He really is. He's a He's a Z. He's a
minus one out of 10. Yes. In fact, I'm
going to show you something. So, while
I'm talking, I'm going to look for it.
So, he endorsed um
uh Cuomo today.
And to me, that is a message to Eric
Adams that buddy, you really need to
drop out of the race. And he's not
dropping out of the race. Let me see if
I can
>> There you go.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. He looks
pretty good because he's dark there. You
can't see much of him. To to not see him
is to love his looks.
>> Yeah. So, um,
>> he's not going to make me reconsider my
heterosexuality. Let's put it that way.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He's a nice enough guy, but
but anyway, he's kind of a a Republican.
He's kind of an independent, whatever.
He's an independent Republican. Uh, but
he did not endorse Eric Adams, who's the
Republican nominee. Or no, he's not the
Republican nominee. It's Curtis Leewa,
>> right? Eric Adams. Eric Adams is the
sitting Democratic mayor who did not
present himself in the primaries because
he was so unpopular. He's at single
digits in the polls. U
>> 9%
>> he's got his ass kicked by a guy nobody'
ever heard of. Um and
>> with a funny name.
>> With a funny name. Yeah. Zoron. Don't
mess with the Zoron.
>> Don't mess with the Zoron.
>> And he ended up uh Yeah. the dude is uh
so they're they're losing it there uh in
the establishment over Mumani
completely.
>> Well, Ted, let me ask you a question.
Today's New York Post had three
different editorials condemning Mumani.
>> It's every day.
>> It's because they're panicking.
>> One of the things that they keep
focusing on is his earlier support for
the defund the police movement,
>> right? Is it is he serious about
defunding the police? And what does that
actually mean? Because it's my
understanding
that it doesn't mean actually defunding
the police, but but it means
transferring some of the the budget for
some police activities to other law
enforcement organizations. County
sheriffs, for example.
>> Well, so yeah, I mean, New York doesn't
really have much in the way of county
sheriffs. We do have we do have one, but
we do have it, but it's like you never
see them. They're they're it's not like
LA where
>> And you don't have a a transportation uh
police.
>> We used to. Yeah. Giuliani got rid of
the transit police. I I I feel like it
was a real blow to public safety because
these were people who knew the subways
inside and out. They could turn they
knew they could chase a suspect into the
tunnel. They knew how to turn off the
power, where to go, and all that. They
were experts in the subway. and crime in
the subway has just not felt manageable
ever since.
>> Okay. But yes, um the the defund the
police uh movement that Mandani
supported at the time, which he's now
backed away from because of the bad
messaging, u was to move some resources
from police departments in general, the
NYPD in particular, over to social
workers who do a lot of the I mean, a
lot of a lot of cop work is work that
cops shouldn't be doing. They don't want
to be
>> like dealing with mentally ill people,
>> for example. And yeah, it the cops
aren't good at it. They don't enjoy it.
It's not why they joined the force. So,
you send social workers out to, hey
dude, it's cold. Let's go to a shelter
tonight. Come with me. It's going to be
all right. You know, that's that's
that's what they they were going to move
that those assets over. It would have
reduced funding for the NYPD, but it
would they would have also had fewer
responsibilities and they would have
had, you know, been been able to focus
more on crime. Um, you know, basically
it was taken as defund the police like
get rid of all it started out as an
academic paper, right? And and basically
it ended up as what's what you know
what's on a title of an academic paper
does shouldn't doesn't make a good
slogan on a protest sign at a
demonstration where you know things need
to be easy to understand and you don't
need to explain it.
>> That's right.
>> So yeah no I mean Mani's he's not a
radical. I mean he's he wants to freeze
the rent. Um that's not a big deal in a
in a city where the rents have been
leaping by.
>> It's quite a popular position. Well, and
the rents are sky high. I mean, John, I
I mean, you haven't been to my place,
but uh you know, I have a two-bedroom
apartment on the Upper West Side of
Manhattan. I pay $5,100 a month. Um you
know, it's it's that's People say, "Oh,
but that's market." I'm like, "Yes, it's
market.
>> That's the problem.
>> But we also have 700,000 people left
during COVID. There's warehous
uh and you know, there's all sorts of
problems with the system." But anyway,
the point is the other and the other
thing is uh free buses which wouldn't
really cost the city that much money
buses transferred for free from the
subway anyway.
>> That's right. Washington started doing
free buses a year ago June and it has
been seamless.
>> Now free free gross he he wants to put
one free um sort of nonprofit not free
nonprofit uh grocery in each of the five
burrows. So, we're talking about in a
city of 8 million people, five
supermarkets. Um, I don't think that's
going to really it's probably not going
to work. I did I hate to say this
because I love that idea as a leftist,
but I dug I I rolled up my sleeves. I
looked into the history of how this work
has worked in other cities in the past.
And generally, the margins on grocery
stores, as your friend uh the the the
grocery magnet could probably say, are
very very low. And you have to have vast
economies of scale that unfortunately uh
you know five little stores aren't going
to have. So it'll probably fail. But you
know it's not a radical
>> it's an experiment to try one per
burrow, right? I mean there's 2.7
million people in my burrow of Manhattan
here. I mean you know we're not all
going to that one store. Sorry
>> Ted. How do you look so healthy and with
this light? I look like I'm dead. I have
a light here and I just don't know. Is
it a Do you have a fluorescent or what
is it?
>> No, it's like a one of those bars that
it's supposed to be dark.
>> Oh, it's the LED maybe. I I have natural
light, but it's filtered uh courtesy of
the Canadian wildfires. Uh it's
>> it's filtered through a layer of haze. I
don't know if you guys are getting that
in DC.
>> Not not yet, but we got it last summer
and you could smell it in the air. It
just chokes you.
>> Yeah. No, I'm I'm I'm suffering. I'm
hurting. I have asthma. It's it's I'm
I'm not a happy camper when this happens
at all.
>> Let me let me add one more thing about
John Katy. He made this idiotic
statement to the Greek American paper,
the National Herald last week that if
Mumani is elected mayor, he's going to
leave and he's going to move to St.
Petersburg, Florida, where he's building
the tallest um residential, you know,
hundstory residential condo thing in in
the state of Florida.
>> Bye.
>> Yeah. Okay. Go. We have plenty. Nobody
cares.
>> Nobody cares. Nobody cares. Just go.
>> The New York Post has been
editorializing repeatedly that, you
know, New York is its billionaires. If
the billionaires leave, we'll all be
screwed. You know, I think I think a lot
of us, 7.9 million of us, we'd like to
we'd like to check that out and see if
that goes. We'll beg for forgiveness and
ask you to come back if it turns out
we're all broke.
>> Sure. But but like I'm somehow doubting
that that's going to be the case
considering the city's been around since
the 1600s kicking ass and taking names
the entire time.
>> That is right.
>> I mean, you know, it's it's they call it
New York [__] city for a reason. Um
so whatever. So So yeah. So I guess uh
so look, so DC though, the DC thing,
unlike the New York City thing, that
could actually happen, right? I mean
Yeah. Yeah, it could actually happen,
which would be a very bad thing. But the
but Trump knows there's no way for for
Washingtonians to defend themselves.
They just can't do it. And then we've
got this I say we I I live just outside.
>> Isn't DC kind of ungovernable? And I
mean, wouldn't that be like an unwinable
job for I mean, we're going to be
talking later on about Trump's plan to
take over aid delivery in Gaza. But
what's with what's with Trump trying to
take over do these things that really no
one can do?
>> Rid Rid pointed out when we first
started talking about Washington that
southeast Washington is one of the most
dangerous [__] holes on the East Coast.
That is absolutely true.
>> 100% true. It is a [__] national
embarrassment.
>> A national embarrassment. ungovernable,
unsecurable,
don't go there even during the daytime.
Um, so why does Trump want to take that
on? You know, there was this
announcement that the Washington, I'm
sorry, that the New York Post had on its
front page this morning saying, "Oh my
god, shootings in New York are at their
lowest level ever in recorded history."
Which isn't true. It's like their lowest
level in in seven years.
Okay, great. Congratulations to Eric
Adams and his 9% support. But what about
Washington? You want to take that on?
That doesn't make any sense.
>> I mean, look, I Okay. Well, you're Look,
you're a Washingtonian. Um, what do you
think? I mean, what do you think is the
solution to DC's big crime problems? And
they are real.
>> Yeah, they are real. Um, I think that
they have to Well, it's it's multiffold.
The answer is multiffold. Number one,
they have to address homelessness. The
homeless situation since CO has been
absolutely ridiculous.
>> Lulu, that's a good comment. It should
be rebranded to back up the police. That
is so
>> That is a great idea.
>> Really good.
>> Then you then you the police unions
would be on your side.
>> That's right.
That is right.
>> Yeah. I mean, honestly, I mean, you
know, I'm not on team cop, but I have
sympathy. I'm a human being. I know cops
and a lot of them are trying to do a
good job and uh you know and honestly
they shouldn't be social workers. Look,
no little little boy or little girl ever
wanted to become a cop thinking like I'm
going to deal with gross homeless guys,
>> right? No. So number one um uh you have
to deal with homelessness, but you also
have to push strongly push education and
vocational training because uh yeah, how
do I do that spectrum? How do I do that
with the white balance? This this light
is on its darkest setting and I don't
know what to do.
>> Um
>> I have to experiment with
>> We'll work on that later. Yeah, maybe.
Yeah, I would ask. That's when I don't
know what to do. I ask AI.
>> Uh that's a great idea. I ask,
>> you know, like I have an LED light. It's
making me look white and washed out.
Meanwhile, I look oily. I'm in If I look
any sworthier, I could be picked up by
ice. Um I don't know.
>> I'll figure this out. Oh, no. No, I made
it worse. Um, so anyway, you got to do
something about vocational training
because you you can't just you can't
just have
people living generation after
generation after generation
um on the streets like this.
>> No, it's it's not tenable.
>> Well, it's and it's gross. And other,
you know, you see in other countries,
you don't see this. You know, they don't
whether it's it's now or during the
Soviet period. It wasn't like that in
Moscow or St. Petersburg. Well, you
couldn't. They would die. Um, it's uh
it's it's it's just ridiculous. Um, all
right. Well, speaking of local
governance, uh, should we talk about
Texas? Um,
>> yeah, the So, that's still going on. Uh,
the, um, they the Texas governor, uh,
Greg Abbott wants to fine the runaway
Democratic legislators. Meanwhile, um,
there's talk
>> he wants to remove some from office.
He's threatened to. You can't do that.
If he did, would that lead to special
elections or would that lead That's what
they would try to do.
>> Or would he try to install a bunch of
Republicans to replace them?
>> I I don't see how you could because
these are Democratic strongholds. I
We're talking about seats in in Austin,
San Antonio, Houston, and Dallas.
>> Well, if a US Senate seat comes up open
though, the governor can fill it can
fill it, right? With
>> I don't think that's the system in in
Texas. I think you have to call a
special election. But just as you
predicted, JB Pritsker welcomed these
these legislators to um Illinois with
open arms and most of them are hiding in
Illinois and he actually gave them
police escorts so that nobody could from
Texas can find them and try to kidnap
them and bring them back.
>> Apparently, there was a death threat or
or some kind of threat against the hotel
where they're purportedly staying.
>> Yes, there was a threat against the
hotel.
>> I mean, you know, that's
>> nuts. Not surprising.
>> And New York, again, as we predicted,
New York, California, and Illinois are
moving forward on their own uh
redistricting to countermand the the
Texas redistricting. There was something
that was so interesting on TV today. Um
what's the White House chief of staff's
name?
>> Oh,
>> uh that woman, the blonde.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Uh I forget her name.
>> She I put it in.
>> Yeah. She she was on Fox today
and I'm sorry, she was on CNN today and
um the interviewer said,
>> why Susie Wilds, that's it.
>> Susie Wilds, thank you. Thank you. Said,
"So why why is the president doing
this?" And and she said that uh he's
only doing what the Constitution
mandates that he do. and and the
interviewer said, "No, the Constitution
mandates that these district lines be
redrawn every 10 years after the after
the census, and they're always drawn,
you know, census is always in a zero
year, and they're always redrawn in time
for the O2 election."
>> Mhm.
>> Or the the two election,
>> the next two Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And um and she said, "But he's
mandated to do this for the Republican
party."
And the interviewer was like,
>> "That's some honesty.
>> Isn't is that was it was unusually
honest."
>> And the interviewer, I don't remember
who it was, said, "But isn't he supposed
to represent the American people?"
>> Well, there's no there's no pretense of
that at all. I mean, I have not in this
term
>> heard President Trump,
>> correct me if I'm wrong, one time
express the thought that he's the
president of all the American people,
uh, whether or not we voted for him.
>> Yeah. which is a standard thing that
presidents say even if it's not really
true.
>> Well, look what he tried to do with FEMA
day before yesterday. There he ordered
this memo to be circulated at FEMA that
um uh disaster funds were not to go to
any um state that voted blue and
>> well or or any or any state or
municipality that uh refuses to do
business with Israel
>> with Israel. That was the second part of
the memo. and um and finally cooler
heads prevailed 2 or 3 hours after the
memo was leaked and it was finally
retracted. But this is not good at all.
I will say though, Donald Trump, you
know that old saying that the broken
clock is right twice a day.
>> Totally.
>> He did something recently that was so
freaking inspired and brilliant. I can't
believe he did it. He named the new
deputy director of the Bureau of
Prisons, right? The BOP,
>> one of the most notoriously corrupt and
dysfunctional and broken organizations
in all of government. It also happens to
be the biggest bureau within the
Department of Justice. He named a former
federal prisoner who just got out of
prison.
>> Oh, yeah. I remember this. After doing
five years on a drug conspiracy charge,
the new deputy director of the Bureau of
Prisons.
>> That's fantastic.
>> The guards union is going berserk.
>> You might be back at Langley soon in
charge at the big desk.
>> Stranger things have happened.
>> Director, Mr. Director.
>> Hey, maybe Tulsi Gabbard, you know,
follows me on Twitter for a reason.
Could
well be. Well, they could definitely No,
I mean, honestly, that is an inspired
choice. I love that he did that.
>> He said he's going to focus on prison
healthcare and food quality,
>> and I wanted to just stand up and start
applauding this guy.
>> Yeah, Jasonith,
>> I'm into it. I'm into it. Um I want to
see I'm I'm really seriously still
crossing my fingers for some major RFK
food regulations. Yeah. uh on
preservatives and [__] all that nasty
crap in our food. Um the I really want
him to get to get cracking. Um John,
let's talk about this is one of my
favorite stories. You know, as you know,
I used to be a banker. And uh Donald
Trump, he he threatened the colleges and
the universities. He shook them down. Uh
Har, by the way, Harvard's pissed. Yeah.
Because Harvard's being asked to pay
half a billion dollars. And they,
according to the Times, they didn't
care. They're like, "Ah, $500 billion.
Whoop you. We have $93 billion in our
endowment. We don't care. No big deal."
But they're pissed off that Brown only
had to pay 50 and it's another Ivy
League school and Colombia only had to
pay 200. And they're like, "Why are we
getting [__] over?" And it's like,
"Well, your anti-semitism, your
was so much worse.
>> 10 times more than Browns or you two and
a half times more than Colombia's." I
mean, it's just a shakeddown and they're
feeling like they've been rolled
because, you know, they have been
>> they have
>> they shouldn't they shouldn't pay
anything. They should say [__] off. And
also, it's like you guys are you go to
Har you are at Harvard. You don't own a
calendar. This guy's not going to be
around in three years. Like all you
John, you know what the courts are like.
It takes forever.
>> Oh my god. Yes.
>> Just sue, drag it out, wait for the
[__] to die or or leave office and
it's all going to go away. Just relax. I
don't understand why they're panicking.
But anyway, now
>> he's going after the banks.
>> So, uh, he's accusing BFA and JP Morgan
Chase and the other big banks of
discriminating particularly against,
well, he says they discriminate against
conservatives. And then he told John
what I thought was a super interesting
story. He said that he had had major
deposits rejected or after he made the
deposits, the banker called, the banks
called and said, "Sorry, Mr. Trump, we
do not want your money."
>> Yep.
>> Claimed it was hundreds of millions of
dollars.
>> Debbanked.
>> Debbanked. Just like Yeah. Like a like a
like a homeless guy in Mexico City.
>> Um and and and he's saying that the
banks discriminate. So now he's going to
go after the banks using regulatory
powers just like he used he sked the de
department of education against the
colleges. He can [__] them. He can
threaten to uh to revoke their banking
licenses and he's going to shake him
down for cash also for his presidential
library. Um it's another shakeddown. So
literally he's going to rob the banks
because after all that's where the money
is as Willie Sutton famously said.
>> Yeah that's right he did.
>> Um so
>> why'd you rob that bank Mr. Sudden
>> John, I know the answer to this
question, but I want to know if you know
the answer to this question. Um, why do
you think the banks told him that they
didn't want his money? And I actually
believe that story.
>> Yeah. He says that uh that the Clintons
and the Obamas uh told them to told them
to
>> why was it?
>> No. Because
>> he's a grifter. Because under the USA
Patriot Act and a lot of other uh
banking securities regulations, it's the
law. If money if if major deposits are
made to your account, whether you're an
individual or a business that you can't
explain in some kind of credible way,
then the bank is going to is going to
they're be they're they're they're going
to be charged with with felonies, right?
So it's you bas so like for example I
moved money to a significant amount of
money from one bank to another after my
mother died and she left me uh money and
I got a call from the bank and they said
uh you know I'm sorry to ask you can I
ask you what this is what this money is
from what how how did you derive it what
do you intend to do with it I thought
god what a bunch of busy bodies what a
bunch of [__] now as it is I had an
answer I I just told the truth truth.
Donald Trump obviously made some big
deposits that he wasn't able to explain
to the satisfaction of his bankers.
That's why they def they they they
kicked out the deposits. The one thing
banks don't want to do is reduce their
nightly float. Uh so if they're turning
your money away, it's because they're
more there's really a problem.
>> Yeah, there's a problem. So what this
indicates to me is that according the
bankers looked at
what he did. They didn't like the cut of
his they didn't like the the the look of
where that cash came from.
>> Yeah.
>> They he he didn't have a good answer for
them. No.
>> Now this is a guy who's been doing major
millions of dollars banking for 50
years.
>> I mean you would think that
>> he would know how to deal with this. I
mean, to me, this if I'm I just don't
know if the Democrats are smart enough
to pick up on this, but to me, there's a
scandal here.
>> Yeah, there very well could be. Tell you
the truth, I don't think the Democrats
would even think up something like this.
Um, or if they did, it would be so hard
to implement to
>> Sure. Sure. Looking into it one thing
up.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's different. Um, but uh
I I I'm not sure that they would be able
to pull it off without there being
fingerprints all over it. That that's
just I think a bridge too far.
>> Oh,
>> maybe.
>> By the way, I guess we should probably
do a quick uh request to if you you guys
already know about our Rumble thing,
please go over to Rumble and also watch
us over there because we literally get
paid like a hundred times more. So
instead of like a penny, for every penny
we'd get like a dollar over there. I
mean, I'm kind of radically simplifying,
but it is really true. If you want to
support the show and you want to help
John and I uh you know, be able to pay
our bills, something that we currently
cannot do, uh it would it would be
really great if you guys would go over
to rumble.com, sign up, and uh I don't
know. I'll put I can put on Robbie.
Robbie, you ready to go on and do your
quick pitch here? Real real quick before
as Robbie's coming on, I wanted to say I
went to the bank this morning. I had an
appointment to go to the bank this
morning because I'm so broke. They took
a $15 monthly maintenance fee, which put
which put me at negative $15 in my
account.
>> So, I had to go back and say, "Guys,
come on. Can you just give me back my
$15?" And they did. Thank goodness. So,
I'm back up I'm back up to zero.
>> Oh my god.
>> Yeah.
>> All right, Robbie. quick quick
explanation and then we'll move on with
the show.
>> But my goal is to help help break that
zero problem. So
>> long story short, just like what Ted
said, Rumble pays a whole hell of a lot
more. Uh Rumble also has come out with a
new change effective today.
>> Uh if you do if you want to be a Rumble
premium subscriber, so what that means
is you see all the premium content,
Tucker Carlson, whoever else, become a
monthly subscriber. However, if you only
care about deprogrammed, you can become
a monthly subscriber on for dprogram for
$5 a month as opposed to 10 and see all
of the premium content that they're
going to start dropping next month. So
that way there's no that that way the
payw wall is cheaper. And the best part
is whenever you become a monthly
subscriber, they keep 100% of that $5.
YouTube whenever someone becomes a
channel subscriber takes 40%
So Rumble gives them everything. So
whenever Ted says that Rumble pays
better, it does pay better. And also
Rumble will not censor what they say.
And speaking of monthly monthly
subscribers, we got three brand new ones
on Rumble, y'all. So we got Jesse, Jesse
Lee, uh Tyler Travesty, and then Tyler
also gifted a a sub to someone over
there on Rumble. So thank you.
>> Thank you so much, guys. Really
appreciate you, Robbie. Thanks for that.
Much appreciated. All right, I'll put
the rumble thing.
>> And Sodon Sin has a question. Sin, thank
you very much there, man. Uh, do you
think Tulsi is stuck between a rock and
a hard place? She's been real quiet
about everything, especially Gaza, and
she seems more like a press secretary
than a DNI.
>> It's when you work for Trump.
>> Yeah, I think I think Yeah, you've hit
it on the head. Um, I think that she's
having to say some things about the
White House that she doesn't really
believe. I think she's had to squatchch
her own positions on many of these
issues like Gaza
um just because she can't have an
independent opinion now. And um this is
this is the price of working for a very
strong personality like Donald Trump.
>> Yeah, no question. Um yeah, I don't
know. It's it's hard to say, you know,
like when you get a call like that. I
mean, first of all, there's the question
like this is your president and I need
you. uh as an American and
>> you have to say yes.
>> I feel like that's your patriotic duty.
>> Yes.
>> Um but on the other hand, I mean
regardless uh of who that president is,
but on the other hand, it's Donald Trump
and you know it's gonna it's going to
end in tears, you know.
>> It just it just it always does.
>> Um
so all right. So the so I I don't know.
I thought that the thing I thought that
was fascinating about the banks. We'll
watch we'll watch that story, but he's
going to definitely shake him down. And
uh right now they've got to be thinking,
well, it's not a question of h of when
we're if we're going to pay, it's a
question of how much we're going to have
to pay.
>> Yeah.
>> That's right.
>> All right. So, you know, um when the
Berlin Wall came down, John, um I was
working at Bear Sterns and my uh
roommate and best friend Dan called me
up and the day that it happened and uh
and we were talking about it and I said,
"What?" And I asked Dan what he said
what do you think and he said well he
said it's kind of like the reunion tour
by at the time in the 80s Crosby Stills
Nash and Young. He's like
>> I went he said I didn't really like any
of Germany's previous collaborations and
I'm not looking forward to the next one.
And uh I feel that way about the news
that uh at the this is the six the 80th
anniversary of the bombing of Hiroshima
that led to the US occupation of Japan
and the imposition of a constitution
that required them not to have a
military for any purpose other than
strictly defensive.
>> And now the Japanese are really looking
to rearm. Uh we've seen some there's
been some predicates to this. they
wanted to uh it's been around, but that
seems to be an a really popular opinion
now in Japan.
>> Yeah. And we saw that
>> to their next uh to their next uh
military operation.
>> We saw that happen in Germany, too.
Right. The Germans have an army, of
course, one it's it's either the biggest
or or it's either the second or third
biggest in NATO uh behind the United
States and Turkey. I can't remember
which one's bigger, but um but they
their their constitution prohibits them
from deploying troops overseas until of
course Bill Clinton insisted on it and
they went to uh Yugoslavia and and you
know had occupation and then Afghanistan
after that. That's right.
>> I want to thank Sen again. Solon Sodon,
thanks again, man. Um do we think the
Saudis were scared of Gaddafi? Oh yeah.
I could tell you with 100% certainty
that they were scared of Gaddafi.
>> What were they scared about? That he was
going to that he was too popular and
that he
>> they were afraid that he was
>> Yes. Yes. And he was so unpredictable
and so popular at the same time.
>> The only thing that made the Saudis back
off on seeking his overthrow when he
made that announcement that he was going
to focus on African unity rather than on
the Middle East. It it's it saved his
life because the Saudis had come to us
and asked us
>> to overthrow him by any means necessary
and that they would pay for everything.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> That's a that's a huge that's a huge
reveal. I didn't know that.
>> Yeah. And we were like, "Yeah, relax. We
don't really have reason." This is 10
years before he was actually overthrown.
>> Yeah. Wow. And sodomized with that
bayonet on on on video. Hillary Clinton
cackled. We saw
>> Yeah. we he died. Um yeah,
>> what what are we I mean so I mean for
people who aren't aware you should go
like look up a list of Gaddafi's
accomplishments. I mean highest literary
rate in a in Africa. Um uh you know
basically oh if you had a wedding that
used to be a massive expense the
government covered your wedding. Um you
got you got free college, free health
care, free everything. all the oil
wealth was nationalized and put towards
the people. Um, you know, Yeah. Of
course he was wildly popular.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. He was wildly popular. And one of
the things that that the Americans were
so afraid of is that he supported a
unified currency for Africa. Um, you
know, in the Middle East, you've got the
Saudis that deal in dollars and the
Kuwaitis deal in dollars and everybody's
buying and selling oil with dollars. And
Kaddafi is like, "No, we need something
like the Europeans have with the Euro."
And the Americans said, "Oh my god,
that's going to wreck us."
>> That's Yeah. By the way, this is very
true. Uh what Nick Otto said changed
women's lives incredibly.
Even though he was Muslim, he he he
ruled like a secular.
>> Yeah, he did. And he famously had a a a
codery of of female bodyguards.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, you know, Quentyn
Tarantino was influenced by that because
they were like crazy awesome hot kung fu
fighting ladies.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. No, I never
>> was he actually responsible for
Lockerby?
>> I always believed that he was.
>> What was the motivation?
>> Um, it it was for killing his daughter
when Reagan killed his daughter in ' 86.
>> Yeah.
>> By by bombing um bombing his tent. He
wasn't in the tent, but his she was like
four or six or something like that.
>> Yeah, that's right. I got into I got
into it with uh John with uh Hannity
about that exact issue. I embarrassed
him because he he claimed that that was
in uh
>> in revenge for um he said that he said
that the Lockerby beat that killing the
kid was in revenge for Lockerby. And I
and I was like in that case I said three
years I said that's what I said I said
Reagan must have been clairvoyant then
it's like that's just not possible did
not happen and they hear them like go to
break go to break
>> yeah no three years before lockerby um
Reed asks why I never converted to Islam
um I studied Islam with one of one of
the faith's most important scholars
living scholars say Hussein Nasser
>> um from Iran. I studied Shiism mostly,
but um now I'm a practicing Greek
Orthodox and
I'm fascinated by the Middle East and
Islam, but it's it's not for me.
>> Yeah. I think the Yeah. No, it's funny
like uh I I had a a pretty famous essay
in the in the 90s called choosing my
religion about a roommate who was
literally trying to she was shopping
around for religions and you know Islam
just when you're shopping for religion
randomly Islam doesn't come up very high
you know it's like you end up like
Buddhism ends up high
>> work involved yeah that's right
>> yeah and yeah and there's and there's
some problematic aspects to Islam
>> for sure I mean all religions But
>> all religions. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean,
>> yeah.
>> A lot of people convert avert though.
>> Yeah.
>> You just answer that question. Um Oh,
wait. I want to get this question. Are
there
>> Marcel? That's a good question.
>> Are there political views shared by
almost anyone everyone at the CIA? And
how much do political views vary there?
You know, the one the one political view
that everybody shared is we all just
hated the Israelis.
All of us. I mean, hating them and being
forced to work with them are two
different things. And we were forced to
work with them. But nobody liked or
respected the Israelis. But I'll tell
you a story that I told
>> conservatives.
>> I assumed that they were and I was
wrong. So what I mean by that is
we never ever ever talked about
politics. It just was not
a thing. It was not a part of the CIA
culture. It didn't matter who the
president was. We were there to serve
the American people. And then on
election day 1992,
I had been in the agency for almost
three years. And I we most of us voted,
you know, early in the morning because
you never know when you're going to get
busy. You might have to stay till
midnight. The president has a question
or you have a briefing or whatever. So,
um,
my branch chief said, "I know we're not
supposed to do this, but I'm really
curious as to who everybody voted for."
And I thought, "Wow, that's bold."
Because I had no idea the ideologies of
the people that I sat 3 feet away from.
Mhm.
>> And I was shocked when we went around
the the little room and it was three for
Bush, three for Clinton, and two for
Perau. I was shocked by it because I
just assumed I was the only progressive.
>> Sure. Yeah. Well, you know, Janna, I I
don't know if I told you the story, but
you know, at when I went at Colombia the
first time around, uh, in ' 84, I went
to the jobs fair and CIA was had a table
at the jobs fair and I recruit and I
don't know how much how true this was.
Um and but when I talked to them they
they asked me you know what they all
sorts of questions and they said um you
know somehow the subject of politics
came up and they they asked me so do you
go to any like socialist or uh left-wing
meetings here on campus. I said yeah all
of them. Yeah. I said I'm I'm basically
a communist. And he's like and the guy
was like he didn't he didn't like that.
It was 1984. It was during Reagan. And
he said well that could be a problem.
And I'm like, "Yeah, but I'm fluent in
French and just because, you know, I'm a
patriot. I love my country. I mean, you
know, being being leftwing or right-wing
should have nothing to do with
anything." And uh, you know, I would die
for my country if need be. And he's
like, "Well, maybe." But he said,
"Mainly," he said, "we recruit Mormons
from Utah.
>> Lots of them."
>> Lots and lots of Oh my god. It's like
every other person you encounter is a is
a Mormon because they speak these funky
languages
that you know they have they all go to
language school.
>> Um and I think it's
>> Oh, and because and because they go on
uh on their missionary work.
>> So you don't have to train them to speak
us or Tajik or whatever. They already
know it.
>> Yeah. And they they don't do anything in
their lives. So they blow right through
the polygraph. They blow right through
the background investigation. They don't
even eat chocolate or drink coffee, let
alone, you know, steal stuff or do
drugs. And so, uh, so they just fell
right through the process. The FBI is
the same way. It's full of Mormons.
>> Well, so it's funny because after that
happened, like 10 years later was the
first time I went to Central Asia. And I
remember, you know, back then, I don't I
don't think it's true anymore, but like
in the early days after independence
from the USSR, all those all the
capitals of those countries had like a
British pub with like CNN International
piped in by satellite. And it was like
the the place to go if you were, you
know, an English-speaking person and you
didn't want to lose your mind and you
just wanted to have like a cold beer and
like watch like something in English.
And anyway, I go to the one in Bishkek
in Kyrgystan and it was just me and this
guy. And so we start talking and he's
like he's American and I'm like and he's
like uh I'm like what do you do? And
he's like oh yeah I work in the uh I'm I
I work for an oil company. I'm like
really and I you work for an oil company
and and you're here. He's like yeah and
I'm like so how long have you been at
the company? Right. is inside the
company, Philip Agy, and he's like, "I
don't know what you're talking about." I
go, "Come on." Like, you're you're an
agent. It's okay. I don't care. It It's
off the record with me, but you know.
And he's like, after a while, he's like,
"Eight years."
>> And I'm like, "Oh my god."
>> And I go and I'm like And he goes, "How
did you know?" And I go, "Because Kystan
doesn't have any oil. You need a better
cover."
>> No, he needed a better cover. Is Right.
Right. I I used to tell people we we
were we were trained to tell people
something so boring that they wouldn't
ask any follow-up questions. So
>> actuarial
>> training. Yeah. Oh, I'm I'm a I'm in the
foreign service. I I do a lot of
training and some import export
negotiations.
>> Although import export I immediately
think of weapons.
>> Oh, right. Well, I was on a flight once
from Milan to Sophia. I was doing a
sensitive operation. So I couldn't go
directly from Athens to Sophia. I had
to, you know, get a different passport
and then get on a plane and go from
Milan.
And so I never talked to people on
planes, but this freaking Italian guy,
this big fat Italian guy I was sitting
next to, just question after question
after question. And he just wasn't
taking my monoselabic, you know, answers
uh as a hint. M
>> so what do you do? I said oh I'm
involved in import export. Oh what are
you in import and export? Uh whatever.
>> The guy's like oh me too.
>> Yeah whatever makes the most money. Um
and he just wouldn't stop. So finally I
said look I smuggle women and cigarettes
from Eastern Europe. Okay. Are you
happy?
And he's like I don't think I approve. I
said I'm not asking for your [__]
approval. You just mind your own
business. Oh, he sat there like this the
rest of the flight. Never said a word.
>> Yeah,
>> that's awesome. I love that so much,
John. Thank you so much for that story.
Makes my day. Okay. And it's and it's
been a long day already. Um, okay. So,
>> wow. Yeah.
>> Let's talk about let's talk about Donald
Trump as always because it's been about
10 minutes. So, the aid situation in
Gaza. We're not going to recap. We all
know it's [__] up. Gaza humanitarian,
the Isra the the it used to be the uh
international community and the UN, they
were kicked out. The Israelis are like,
"We can do a better job. It all they do
is kill the people who come to their
shitty food sites." Um and so it's
totally [__] up. Now Trump says that
he wants to take it over himself. Steve
Witco, his his envoy, says the US will
take direct control of distribution of
humanitarian aid in uh in Gaza. Um
can I just say that like the devil is in
in the details here?
>> You can say that again.
>> Is he going to do this? Is this like how
would it look like? What are the risks
that are entailed? I mean, this is the
same US government that tried to install
um, you know, a a pier and it like got
blown away in a storm um and spent
millions of dollars on it and almost
lost a guy doing it. Um, I mean, how
>> I can't imagine that this is a real
plan. First of all, we don't have the
the assets on the ground to be able to
do it. We would have to essentially
invade Gaza,
>> right?
which we could we could and have the
military do it
>> right and the Israelis would have to be
okay with it because hilariously it is
occupied territory by our ally so we'd
be you know the Israelis would have to
say okay and they would essentially they
would essentially be yeah relinquishing
control
>> that's right that's right
>> we'd have to come in by land I mean look
it's the US we could do it right we
could distribute massive amounts of aid
um and we could do it extremely well and
very quickly, I bet.
>> That's right.
>> And it really has to be trucked in. It
can't be air dropped.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Dropping it by air just it doesn't
work. It never works. It never has
worked. No. It has to be trucked in. And
the Israelis just won't let the trucks
through.
>> I mean, so to me, I guess what's more
interesting than the plan, which I can't
imagine once the U once Trump hears
about what would be required that he'll
go through with it. um you know like you
might lose Americans, they might be
shot. Um you know, it's also it exposes
the Israelis for what they've been
doing, right? I mean, if there's any
doubt in anyone's mind, it's like, well,
>> you didn't want to let food in, but we
can bring in food, which means you could
have brought in food, and you chose not
to. I mean, you already have uh former
Prime Minister Naftali Bennett writing
that Israel is now a leper state in the
United States, and he's a right-winger.
Uh saying that it's completely that
Israel's completely isolated from the
world. That's right. That everybody he's
they've already lost the Democratic
Israel's lost the Democratic party.
They're in danger of losing the
Republican party. That the whole world
hates Israel now. He's right. He's 100%
right. So, um, this would just increase
that narrative. I mean, to me, it's this
is this is a symptom of what's going on,
right? But basically, Trump looks at
this and says, "Oh, [__]
>> I'm getting my Israeli buddy is going to
drag me under, isn't he?"
>> Did you see the new poll that came out
from Gallup by Gallup uh yesterday?
It was the numbers were shocking. The
only the only Americans who support
Israel are Americans aged 55 and older.
That's it. Everybody else is going huge,
not just for the the Palestinians, but
for the Iranians versus the Israelis as
well.
>> Yeah.
>> So, they're they're losing Americans
very quickly here. Very quickly.
>> Wow. Yeah. No, I mean it's it's
terrifying. And then also I wanted to
talk a little bit about the uh situation
with the um statehood offers right so
you know the French have have they
started this they and Emanuel Macarron
said okay we will recognize um Palestine
that's pretty much without strings but
uh Canada and the UK
>> lots of strings involved right so
basically in with Canada and the UK this
the uh requirement ment would be and
this is something that like the Arab
League letter said also um basically
they'd they'll recognize the Palestinian
Authority not Hamas um that the a
Palestinian state a future Palestinian
state would have to be completely
demilitarized
um so no military and that the uh
Israeli security would be prioritized in
that arrangement and that the new state
would have to cooperate with Israel when
it wants to come in and look for someone
that they don't like or kill them or
whatever. Um, it's not sovereignty,
right? I mean, a sovereign state has its
own military. Um, and you know, but but
that seems to be like what the what's on
offer now from the West. I mean I mean,
don't get me wrong, the the Palestinians
are at least diplomatically better off
than they were a year ago.
>> Sure. But but it seems to me like this
isn't really this is kind of like the
deal that like Zionists always say
Arafat had a deal. He didn't take it.
And when you look at the details you're
like no one would have taken it. I mean
it was going to turn the West Bank into
a bunch of bantans separated into like
16 different zones. The Israelis were
going to be able to come and go as they
please. They were to have no military
whatsoever. I mean, it was going to be
basically they're going to have the same
independence as Loto surrounded by
>> completely surrounded.
>> Yeah, that's exactly right. That's
exactly right. Now, the Palestinians
don't make it any easier for themselves
by I shouldn't say the Palestinians, the
the the Palestinian Authority doesn't
make it any easier for itself be by
refusing to hold an election. I I made a
joke the other day on the show that
>> that uh Mahmud Abbas is, you know, 19
years into a four-year term.
>> Mhm.
>> And uh he's decrepit old man and he
needs
>> He's a million years old. He's like 90,
isn't he?
>> Yeah. He's almost 90.
>> Yeah.
>> He's got to go. And corruption. Oh my
god. With a capital C. That's got to
end.
>> Yeah. Not to mention, you know, it gives
cover. It's a It's a Vichi regime is
what it is. And it gives cover to the p
to every time Israeli settlers are in
there killing the lo killing the locals.
Um you know John did you hear about this
crocodile story?
>> Oh my god. So this is wacky. So in uh
back in so basically
before 2013, there was an a crocodile
farm that Israeli settlers created in
the West Bank um to basically harvest
their you know their skins and make
handbags or shoes out of them or
whatever. um the the the plate. But then
in 2013, the uh it went out of business
because the Israeli government passed an
animal rights law that said that the
Nile crocodile wasn't was a protected
species. You got to love Israel. They
they kill babies like like they're going
out of style, but the crocodiles are
protected.
>> Got to save those.
>> Got to save Mr. Bitey. So then the croc
so here's the thing. It goes out of
business. the the the Israeli settler
who owns the farm just leaves it, dips
on it, doesn't give a [__] about it,
leaves the crocodiles to their own
device. Today there's 200 crocodiles
there. Some of them, this place is six
miles away from the Jordan River. There
was concern several of them have escaped
and have made have gone on the lamb. who
was concerned that they might make it to
the Jordan River and attack Jordanians
and cause an international incident. And
I'm like, okay, so they so they went in
today and killed all 200 crocodiles.
>> Oh my god.
>> And the is and but the but this is it's
against Israeli law to do it because
they're protected. They're Nile
crocodiles. Obviously, they could be
returned to Egypt or whatever um and
dumped in the in the river. But anyway,
so it's just a wacky story. But there's
also like, so wait a minute, you guys
are not just moving your kids over there
and killing the locals. You're moving
dangerous animals to occupied stolen
land. I mean, the thing is so bizarre.
Did
>> you see the announcement from this zoo
in Denmark yesterday?
>> Yeah. to, you know, plea, please bring
your pets that you don't want anymore
because we need to feed them to the
lions, you know, circle of life and all.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly.
>> People are like, "What?"
>> Yeah, that's right. Although, in
fairness to the Danes, uh they they they
said that they're not going to like take
my cat and let him run around the cage
while the tiger chases him, right? They
would euthanize him first.
>> Yeah. And just toss him in there.
>> And then toss him in there.
>> It's It's such a such a crazy story.
>> I was in Addis Ababa one time. Ethiopia
and I went to the zoo because I had a
half a day, you know, to do nothing.
There's really nothing to do.
>> That must have been a sad, a sad story.
>> There were these three or four zoo
workers that were like pulling and
pushing this screaming
donkey
into the lion's cage. And the thing is
like you doing everything it can to
fight being pushed into the lion's cage.
And then they just
>> Oh yeah. And the Lions tore it to
pieces. I watch I have to admit I would
want to watch that.
>> It was It was bad.
>> I would want to watch that.
>> They gouge you if you're a Westerner.
It's like a nickel to get in if you're
Ethiopian and then it's like a dollar to
get in if you're not.
>> Those I mean those those foreign zoos
though, they're rough like in Central
Asia or whatever.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh yeah.
>> It's not up to the high standards. Well,
that's what the Central Park Zoo used to
be like here in New York.
>> It was awful. Um, so
>> yeah, bad.
>> So, um, let's talk about more Israel
stuff. So, I thought this was
interesting. Um, so it turns out that,
uh, in the 12-day war between Iran and
Israel that actually, um, the Iranians
blew up a lot of [__] and killed some
Israelis. Um, and there the damage was
quite substantial.
>> Yes.
>> Now, we haven't heard much about that
here in the West. No. But what's coming
out now is that in Israel, nobody knows.
It's been completely censored,
>> and uh and so the Iranians, I mean,
obviously, I mean, the Israelis
obviously live in a very small country.
I assume they all talk to each other and
word gets out.
>> But I mean, what does that say about
this so-called democracy?
>> Yeah.
>> That information is so carefully
controlled.
>> Yeah. It's no democracy. It's certainly
no functioning democracy when you have
what is it a dozen different parties
that are all represented in parliament
and it's literally impossible to uh to
have a a functioning government that's
not a coalition
and then everything is is trumped by by
military concerns anyway on top of it.
Israel is no democracy.
Wow. Yeah. So, um, yeah. I mean, and I
think honestly that control has been
very effective. It's part of the reason
that Israel ordinary Israelis don't
really know
>> just to what extent they've become, you
know, their country is a pariah.
>> Yep. Yep. Agreed.
>> Interesting story. Speaking of Israel
tangentially, but its effects here in
the US Stan so at Stanford University,
they have a school newspaper still,
thank God, and a really interesting
lawsuit. So it turns out the editors
noticed that a lot of columnists and
wouldbe student journalists have either
refused to join the paper, refuse to
submit articles or quit be and it's
become a serious problem because a lot
of them are international students and
they're afraid that if they comment on
not just Gaza but anything else that the
Trump administration doesn't like that
they could be deported. And they have
reason to believe that because of course
the Trump administration has attempted
and has kid has had ICE kidnap uh people
off the street for writing columns in
the uh you know in in the in a student
newspaper. Y that's been enough. So, the
Stanford paper is now suing uh ICE and
the Trump administration for for for
their uh for their squaltched first
amendment rights, which is of course the
only thing that the First Amendment
really is good for is protecting you
from government censorship, which is
usually in the past never direct
usually, right? Um, like my case with
the LA Times was unusual because the L
the LAPD, which is a government entity,
purchased the LA Times parent company.
So, it was like basically a first
amendment case by proxy. But that
doesn't usually happen. Usually, someone
calls that calls the paper says fire
John Kuryaku and then they do. But you
can't sue the government. You can only
sue your employer and the employer is
not a government entity. here the
government entity is directly stifling
the speech of the student newspaper.
I don't know. I wish them well. I don't
know if it's going to um I don't know if
it's going to work. Suing government is
hard.
>> It's very hard. Yeah. But man, this is
this is so scary. And we still have
three and a half years of this left,
you know, and and even then will cooler
heads prevail again? I don't know. This
idea that you could just get rid of
people whose opinions you don't like.
Very scary. And you know, we forgot to
mention that Trump announced today he's
going to meet with both Putin and
Zalinski. Um
>> Oh, yeah. That's huge.
>> Yeah.
>> That just broke. That just broke.
>> Yeah. And uh the
>> So, is it going to be at the same time
or in two separate meetings?
>> No, two separate meetings. and and the p
the the Kremlin is saying it's because
they're just tired of Trump being on
their back all the time. So, they're
going to at least listen to what he has
to say. So, this is a good thing.
>> Oh, it's a very good thing. I mean, I
wish this had happened a long time ago.
>> Me, too.
>> Um, so I guess I mean, Trump usually
takes a more active role in
international diplomacy. We saw that
with North Korea during his first term.
Um I you know is this one of those
things where he tried he's like well
thank you Steve Whitoff but I've got to
like roll I've got to take care of this
myself manto man you know Vladimir and I
can work it out.
>> I think so.
>> I don't think Putin will let him. Putin
is not willing to be bullied and Trump
thought he could bully Putin into a
settlement.
>> No Putin's not bullyable.
>> No. But I mean what if but what if Trump
goes over there? Is there an inducement?
I mean is there a deal? Is there a
structure that will work for the Russian
Federation and I mean presumably for the
support Ukraine?
>> I used to think so. I used to think so.
That the Russians get to keep the
Donbass. Uh they get to keep the Crimean
Peninsula. Um that the Ukrainians won't
uh be allowed to join NATO but they
would be fasttracked in the European
Union. I mean everybody said that was
the deal. And what if it was that and
like maybe Russia pays
um reconstruction costs for Ukraine?
>> Oh, that would be actually
I don't know why Putin would agree to
something like that, but I think the
Ukrainian jump at it.
>> Yeah, they do.
>> They do. From all that gas they're
selling to the Indians.
>> Yeah. And to the Chinese. Um Yeah. So, I
feel like I mean they could do that,
right? I mean that I feel like that
would be like okay yes um you know
you've lost territory but you're being
compensated.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like view it like a sale of Alaska.
>> Yes. Could be.
>> Could be.
>> That's the kind of I mean we know Trump.
You watch the show. You're welcome. You
can take that for free.
>> Speaking of watching the show, I have a
Google alert on myself. I always have. I
was shocked day before yesterday to see
that you and I were quoted on NPR.
>> No way.
>> Yeah. I I meant to send it to you. I was
shocked.
>> We were quoted on It said It said Ted R
and editorial cartoonist and CIA
whistleblower John Kuryaku discussed
whatever. I can actually call it up
because I saved it. I saved it. I was
like, "What? I gotta tell Ted about
this."
>> Wow, that's great.
Well, we have so
>> shocking.
>> Uh if uh you Mr. or Miz or MX NPR is uh
listening or watching right now, thank
you very much for the hat.
>> Yeah, thanks for that.
>> We appreciate it. And if you ever need
us as a guest, one or one or both, let
us know.
>> That is right.
>> Wow. That is cool.
>> I I'll find it. I'll find it. I saved
it.
>> That's fantastic. Do you remember which
show it was or was it like just a a
written piece?
>> Here it is. Google alert. Uh it was
it was about Palestinian food aid.
Um and it says here, hold on. Open a new
link.
Enter.
Verifying that you are a human.
Okay.
full article.
Dog gone it. Sorry this is taking so
long.
>> Um Tom, it's the graveyard book is
actually John's book. So yeah that
question. What happened to it? He wants
to
>> I was yelling at my editor yesterday
like you guys are killing me here. I
sent you the manuscript three years ago.
Octo of April. You told me at the
absolute latest it would be out on July
31st. And here we are in August. So this
is it's a threeinut listen.
>> It's in it's entitled in Gaza more
Palestinians are killed while awaiting
food.
>> And then in the in the article
um
>> Okay. While you're at work.
>> Yeah. Talking about the famine is
unfolding and that you and I discussed
it on the show.
>> That's it. That's it.
>> That's so random.
>> Like we're a mainstream, you know, news
source that NPR turns to for uh
>> Well, of course, obviously. Goes without
saying.
>> Um that's amazing though. So great. Um
hey, so Dana wants to know, do we think
Epste was a double agent?
>> Uh you I assume you mean for like
Mossad, right?
>> Oh, no. I think he was an agent for
Mossad. It's possible that he was a
double agent for the CIA.
Absolutely possible. And and the only
reason I say that is because of Alex
Aosta saying that he got that he had to
give he had to give him a sweetheart
deal because Epstein was intelligence.
>> Yeah. And what else could that mean?
>> What does that mean?
>> It has to mean American intelligence.
that it has to me mean American
intelligence because there are only two
people that Alex Aosta would have
reported to at the time. Um Alberto
Gonzalez and George W. Bush.
>> It's certainly it's certainly possible,
right? No question.
>> Yeah.
>> Um Marcel wants to know, is either side,
Russia or Ukraine, going to budge?
>> Both sides have reinforced their goals
over and over without change over the
whole war. That's true.
>> Yeah. Um, but I do feel like the facts
on the ground are the facts on the
ground. And that that's not going to
change. I mean, you know, I can't think
of any historical precedent where you'd
have a situation like this where, for
example, Ukraine would get its way and
Russia would withdraw from a significant
amount of territory. Not after a
situation like this. Yeah.
>> And conversely, I can't imagine a
situation where, you know, Ukraine is
going to just be like blly give up claim
to a substantial 20% of its territory
and be like, "Yeah, we don't care.
Whatever. Easy, no harm, no foul." I
mean, those demands are going to remain.
That's why I suggest the money thing
then. Like, that's right.
>> It lets it gives it gives the Ukrainians
a way to save face.
>> That's right. you know, and I wanted to
I'm sorry to jump to another subject,
but I know we're very short on time now,
but I wanted to say something. There was
a very very important uh demonstration
in uh in Australia a couple of days ago
that was led by Julian Assange. That was
one thing that I wanted to say. He's
finally getting out there and taking a
leadership position in some of these um
these things. And there's also a very
important um march coming up in support
of Mary Castacadus or Costakilis who is
I'm not over stressing this. She is the
Walter Kronhite of Australia.
>> Um she's being sued by a bunch of um
Zionist groups for calling what's
happening in Gaza a genocide. and um she
risks actually being imprisoned
for anti-semitism
for saying that what's happening in Gaza
is a genocide. They have some [__] up
laws in in Australia.
>> I guess those laws are obviously very
similar to England's, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly right.
>> So, yeah, I mean it's very it's very
easy to get on the wrong side of a
liable law.
>> Oh, it really is. It really is. So, good
luck to both Julian Assange and to Mary.
Uh, they deserve our support.
>> Uh, for sure. Um, hey, so there's a
there's some uh there's some interesting
paranoia
uh paranoid articles about China as
using AI to uh basically do research and
oppo research against American uh
politicians with a view towards possibly
just being able to leverage them and and
and all this. And basically,
>> I read all these articles and and
basically they seem to have about as
much meat as the articles talking about
anti-semitism in Gaza protests on
American campuses. You're just looking
in vain. Like, come on. Like, where is
it? Where is it? I mean,
>> they must have nicer editors than I ever
had because my editors would never have
published something that had no
citations whatsoever. But it's all just
random speculation. It's all breezy and
airy. So yes, there is a country named
China. Yes, there is a thing called AI.
Yes, you can use AI to gather
information about things and people. But
so [__] what?
>> So what
>> am I am I What am I missing? Am I
stupid?
>> Exactly. Exactly.
Who cares?
>> I mean, yeah. It's just sort of like the
idea like China's doing stuff. They're
big and scary and dangerous because
yellow menace.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> I just was hoping that that was
>> No. Oh my god. Chinese.
>> All right.
>> Okay.
>> Are we Are we deprogrammed?
>> I'm deprogrammed.
>> I am deprogrammed, too. We will be back
Friday. I'll be in Montana. Um uh I have
a book signing there, but I have time
because of the time difference. uh it
should be okay. Uh if not, we might have
to rejigger the time. But anyway, 5
o'clock Eastern time uh in uh 3:00
Central time. If you're in Callispel,
Montana, come and see me at Barnes &
Noble at 1 p.m. Friday and 1 p.m. on
Saturday. And uh thank you very much for
watching. We'll be back next week also
Monday, Wednesday, Friday. That's our
schedule. 5:00 PM. I'm Ted R. That's
John Kuryaki. You've been watching D
program. Please like, follow, and share
the show. Reed is saying, uh, we need
some guests on this show. Hey, if you
have any ideas for guests, um, you know,
anyone,
>> thank you, Forson.
>> I've got a bad stomach ache.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it's uh, that sucks.
>> Getting a transfusion tomorrow. It's
going to make me myself again. Yeah,
>> I remember I had trans I had a
transfusion once.
>> I got to have a whole bunch of them.
>> Oh, man. All right. Well, I hope I hope
all it's all the best blood.
I hope so.
>> All right, John. Good luck. I'll talk to
you tomorrow.
>> Thanks, buddy. Safe travels.
>> You, too.
>> Uh, let's see. No outro end stream. They